Ben Anderson

design.benanderson@gmail.com · (720) 297-6474 Portfolio Site LinkedIn Profile

Hello! My name is Ben Anderson 👋 and I've been designing SaaS web apps for seven years. Since 2021 I've been focused on design systems:

UI components and patterns that are highly usable, consistent, scalable, responsive and accessible.

Figma libraries that empower designers to deliver their best work, fast.

Documentation and training resources that equip anyone in the org to make smart, systems-oriented design choices.

Design-to-Dev processes that ensure a precise and strategic transition from vision to code.

Experience

JumpCloud <

Senior Product Designer, Platform Experience (August 2021 – Present)

Stratus Web Design System serves all of JumpCloud's web consoles and 18+ UX designers. I created an ecosystem of web UI components and patterns to scale across our platform, Figma libraries with 80+ UI components, documentation and training resources, and handoff processes to translate designs into Vue-based code.

JumpCloud MTP allows IT administrators to serve multiple client organizations from a single pane of glass. I've led UX for this product since 2021, focusing on new features like integrations, license usage and payment history. I also developed new UI components and patterns for navigation, list and detail views, status cards, bulk actions, and quick actions for application across all other JumpCloud platforms.

Password Manager lets JumpCloud end users securely store and share passwords. I supported this project by designing key flows for onboarding, user enrollment, shared folder management, and usage insights. It also provided a great opportunity to apply design system patterns and new UI components.

Asset Directory helps IT admins to provision, track and manage all of the hardware and software assets used by employees across their org. I supported this project by designing list and detail views, asset creation flows, user assignment flows, and usage insights.



Senior Product Designer (July 2019 – April 2021) Product Designer (March 2018 – June 2019)

GlobalMeet Webcast is a live video streaming platform for enterprise companies. I led a vision-oriented redesign for this web app by creating all new UI, navigation and page structures, as well as flows for event creation, event delivery, recording, chat and analytics. I also turned all that into a high-fidelity prototype for user testing and a promotional video.

GlobalMeet Mobile is a platform for web conferencing and unified business communications. I led UX for these iOS and Android apps from 2018 to 2020, focusing on UI updates and new features like smart notifications, messaging, calling and video conferencing.

$\textbf{ReadyTalk}\ \bigcirc$

User Experience Designer (January 2017 – February 2018) Visual Designer (December 2015 – December 2016)

Illuminate Webcast is a live and simulated-live video streaming platform purpose-built for marketers. I led UX for this new web app by creating branding, UI, navigation and page structures as well as flows for event creation, event delivery, recording, chat and white label customization.

ReadyTalk.com provides marketing and support information for ReadyTalk's conferencing and webcast products. I redesigned the site to make it easier for potential customers to find the right solutions, understanding pricing, dive into technical specs and self-serve or connect with sales. It was also a great opportunity to update the visual identity while building on existing brand recognition.

Foxden Video Conferencing allows users to virtually meet and share content without downloads or plugins. I designed the visual identity, website, marketing collateral, and promotional videos.



Industrial Designer (July 2013 – November 2015)

Nuby makes toys, teethers and feeding products for babies and toddlers. I designed new products from sketch to refined drawings, to 3D models, renders and prototypes, to materials and finishes, and finally to manufactured pieces for worldwide distribution.

Education

University of Bradford 🎓

MBA - Innovation, Enterprise and Circular Economy (2015 – 2018)

Savannah College of Art and Design 🎨



BFA - Industrial Design (2007 – 2011)

Tools

Web

HTML + CSS (I like to mock with markup whenever possible)

UX

Figma (preferred), Sketch, XD, ProtoPie, Usertesting.com

Adobe

Photoshop, Illustrator, AfterEffects

View my work at <u>andersonxd.com</u>